Mss.Rec.138 Mss.Rec.138
American Philosophical Society
Indian Language Field Recordings
Bulk, 1950-1954
1941, 1945, 1948, 1950-1951, 1954, 1956-1957, 1962, 1964
Mss.Rec.138
American Philosophical Society
44.0 Reel(s)
44 sound tape reels (22 hr., 18 min.): analog, 3 3/4 & 7 1/2 ips, half track & full track, mono: 5 in., 7 in.
Abrams, Yendi
Bear Child, Lewis
Buck, Joshua
Bull Child, George
Butler, Sadie
Concha, Eliseo
Cornplanter, Jesse J.
Curry, Ed
Dowdy, Herb
Elm, Ray
Fairchild, Louis
Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
Gibson, Simeon
Hecote, Ellen
Jacob, John Ely
Jimerson, Avery
Jimerson, Danny
Jimerson, Lester
Johnny John, Amos
Johnny John, Chauncey
Johnny John, Richard
Johns, Albert
Johnson, Danny
Jones, Albert
Kurath, Gertrude Prokosch
Lang, Tom
Lewis, Tom
Logan, Joseph
Preston, Jack
Redeye, Nelson
Running Crane, Geneva
Running Crane, John
Schenadoah, Rodney
Smith, George
Smoke, Percy
Stevens, Fannie
Sundown, Roland
War Bowl
Conditions Governing Access
This material has access restritions. Please consult a curator for details.
Bartlett, Charles; Gaus, Dorothy Shipley, 1928-; Allegheny River (Pa. and N.Y.); Buffalo dance; Cayuga Indians--Music; Cayuga Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Crow language; Hopi Indians--Music; Hopi Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Hopi Indians--Social life and customs; Indians of North America--New Mexico--Government relations; Indians of North America--New Mexico--Music; Iroquois Indians--History--17th century; Jemez dance; Jemez Indians--Music; Klamath Indian Reservation (Or.); Klamath Indians--Government relations; Klamath Indians--History; Klamath Indians--Land tenure; Klamath Indians--Medicine; Klamath Indians--Music; Klamath Indians--Politics and government; Klamath Indians--Social life and customs; Modoc Indians--History; Modoc Indians--Politics and government; Modoc Indians--Social conditions; Modoc Indians--Wars, 1873; Names, Geographical--New York (State); Names, Geographical--Pennsylvania; Navajo dance; Navajo Indians--Music; New York (State)--Description and travel--Early works to 1800; Onondaga dance; Onondaga Indians--Music; Paiute Indians--History; Paiute Indians--Politics and government; Powwows--New Mexico; Pueblo Indians--Government relations; Seneca dance; Seneca Indians--Folklore; Seneca Indians--Music; Seneca Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Seneca Indians--Social life and customs; Seneca language; Siksika Indians--Music; Siksika Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Siksika language; Song cycles; Sound recordings; Sun--Rising and setting--Songs and music; Taos dance; Taos Indians--Music; Taos Indians--Politics and government; Taos Indians--Social life and customs; United States. Treaties, etc. 1864 Oct. 14; Western Apache dance; Western Apache Indians--Music; Zuni Indians--Music
- Seneca Songs and Dances, 1941, 1956; Mss.Rec.138.1; 2.0 Reel(s)
  - Songs relating to the Iroqouis Midwinter Festival, 1956-01-08; 1941; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:45; Buck, Joshua; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gibson, Simeon; Johnny John, Chauncey; Jones, Albert; Logan, Joseph
    Scope and Contents note
    Consists of songs and speeches selected from "Songs from the Iroquois longhouse," ed. William N. Fenton (Washington, D.C.: Library of Congress, 1942) interspersed with English translations and explanations by William N. Fenton.
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Sound tape reel) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Seneca Indians--Music; Seneca Indians--Religion; Seneca Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Six Nations Indian Reserve No. 40 (Ont.)
  - Iroquois Confederacy: Green Corn Dance, 1956-08; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:12:47; Elm, Ray; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Lewis, Tom; Smoke, Percy
    Onondaga dance; Onondaga Indian Reservation (N.Y.); Onondaga Indians--Music; Onondaga Indians--Rites and ceremonies
- Proof Readings, February 1964; Mss.Rec.138.2; 2.0 Reel(s)
  - Dictation for proof reading against original of "Captain Hyde's Observation of the Five Nation at New York, 1698" [1 of 2], 1964-02-14; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:03:40; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
    William F. Fenton dictating for proof reading against original of William N. Fenton, editor, "Captain Hyde's Observation of the Five Nations at New York, 1698." (_American Scene Magazine_, Tulsa, Oklahoma. Gilcrease Institute of American History and Art, 1965.)
    Iroquois Indians--History--17th century; New York (State)--Description and travel--Early works to 1800
  - Dictation for proof reading against original of "Captain Hyde's Observation of the Five Nation at New York, 1698" [2 of 2], 1964-02-14; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:28; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
  - Dictation for proof reading against original of "The Journal of James Emlen, Kept on a Trip to Canandaigua, New York, September 15 - October 30, 1794, to Attend A Treaty Between the United States and the Six Nations" [1 of 2], 1964-02-25; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:35:59; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
    William F. Fenton dictating for proof reading against William N. Fenton, editor, "The Journal of James Emlen, Kept on a Trip to Canandaigua, New York, September 15 - October 30, 1794, to Attend A Treaty Between the United States and the Six Nations." (_Ethnohistory_ 12(4): 279-342, 1965)
    Iroquois Indians--History--18th century; Iroquois Indians--Treaties, 1794; New York (State)--Description and travel--Early works to 1800
  - Dictation for proof reading against original of "The Journal of James Emlen, Kept on a Trip to Canandaigua, New York, September 15 - October 30, 1794, to Attend A Treaty Between the United States and the Six Nations" [2 of 2], 1964-02-25; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 01:25:08; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
- Allegany Singing Society, June 4, 1957; Mss.Rec.138.3; 2.0 Reel(s)
  - Singing session at Ed Curry's, June 4, 1957 [1 of 3], 1957-06-04; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:43; Curry, Ed; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
    Allegany Indian Reservation (N.Y.); Seneca Indians--Music
  - Singing session at Ed Curry's, June 4, 1957 [2 of 3], 1957-06-04; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:26:37; Curry, Ed; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
  - Singing session at Ed Curry's, June 4, 1957 [3 of 3], 1957-06-04; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:21:40; Curry, Ed; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
- Sour Springs Cayuga, Dark Dance, 1945; Mss.Rec.138.4; 2.0 Reel(s)
  - Dark Dance, Sour Springs Cayuga [1 of 2], 1945; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:33:35; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Jacob, John Ely; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950
    Program was originally recorded on phonograph discs, and later transfer to reel-to-reels. This recording was copied in 1955 from original reels at the Library of Congress.
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Phonograph record) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Cayuga Indians--Music; Cayuga Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Six Nations Indian Reserve No. 40 (Ont.)
  - Dark Dance, Sour Springs Cayuga [2 of 2], 1945; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:20:18; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Jacob, John Ely; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950
- Seneca, Allegany: Dark Dance, August 17, 1948; Mss.Rec.138.5; 3.0 Reel(s)
  - Dark Dance, a medicine society, at Coldspring [1 of 3], 1948-08-17; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:51; Abrams, Yendi; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Johnny John, Amos; Jones, Albert; Stevens, Fannie
    Opening speech is described on the original tape box as a tobacco invocation to the Little People. This recording contains significant periods of inaudible or minimally audible conversation. Opening invocation spans from :10 - 4:00. Music starts at 9:35 - 20:08, and again at 21:10 - 24:13.
    Allegany Indian Reservation (N.Y.); Seneca Indians--Music; Seneca Indians--Rites and ceremonies
  - Dark Dance (Part II) Joking [2 of 3], 1948-08-17; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:27; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Jones, Albert; Stevens, Fannie
  - Dark Dance at Coldspring [3 of 3], 1948-08-17; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:26:46; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Johnny John, Chauncey; Jones, Albert; Stevens, Fannie
    "This canto announces the arrival of the Little People who come from 10 nights away from the rocky places, through meadows, over swamps and streams." Program concludes with an account by the researcher in English of the origin of the Dark Dance.
    Allegany Indian Reservation (N.Y.); Seneca Indians--Folklore; Seneca Indians--Music; Seneca Indians--Rites and ceremonies
- Seneca: Songs, Dances, and Place Names, 1948, 1950; Mss.Rec.138.6; 5.0 Reel(s)
  - Seneca place names on the Allegheny River, 1948-07; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:25:42; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Johnny John, Chauncey
    Allegany Indian Reservation (N.Y.); Allegheny River (Pa. and N.Y.); Names, Geographical--New York (State); Names, Geographical--Pennsylvania; Seneca language
  - Corn Dance and discussion, 1948-08-26; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:16:41; Cornplanter, Jesse J.; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Kurath, Gertrude Prokosch
    Performance of the Seneca Corn Dance, followed by a discussion of its history and current use.
    Onondaga Indians--Music; Seneca dance; Seneca Indians--Music; Seneca Indians--Social life and customs; Tonawanda Indian Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Hand-in-Hand Dance, 1948-08-26; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:51; Cornplanter, Jesse J.; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
    Seneca dance; Seneca Indians--Music; Tonawanda Indian Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Coldspring Longhouse Midwinter Festival: On the Husk Faces and their appearance on VIth night, 1950-01-29; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:21:55; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
    A report given by the researcher regarding events seen at and surrounding the Seneca Coldspring Longhouse Midwinter Festival. Original recording contains a several minutes of silence. At time marker 3:45, three seconds of silence been inserted to represent 3:20 of silent tape that has been deleted. This is followed by 2:48 of tape with faintly audible speech. Fully audible speech recommences at time marker 6:36.
    Allegany Indian Reservation (N.Y.); Seneca dance; Seneca Indians--Music; Seneca Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Seneca Indians--Social life and customs
  - Wa?eno?e:?, War Dance, 1950-01-29; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:43; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
    A report given by the researcher regarding the history and use of the Wa?eno?e:? dance.
    Allegany Indian Reservation (N.Y.); Seneca dance; Seneca Indians--History; Seneca Indians--Music; War songs
  - Coldspring Longhouse Midwinter Festival: VIth to the VIIIth days, 1950-02-18; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:56; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
    A report given by the researcher regarding events seen at and surrounding the Seneca Coldspring Longhouse Midwinter Festival.
    Allegany Indian Reservation (N.Y.); Seneca dance; Seneca Indians--Music; Seneca Indians--Religion; Seneca Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Seneca Indians--Social life and customs
  - Wenothowi'sas: Women's Rite, 1948-08; 05-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:45; Butler, Sadie; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; John, Richard; Johns, Albert; Stevens, Fannie
    A performance of the Wenothowi'sas Women's Rite, followed by a report by the researcher on its content and origin story. There is a 6-second silent gap on the original recording, beginning at 19:09, which has been retained.
    Allegany Indian Reservation (N.Y.); Seneca dance; Seneca Indians--Folklore; Seneca Indians--Music; Seneca women--Rites and ceremonies
- Seneca Dances and Songs, 1950-1951, 1954; Mss.Rec.138.7; 5.0 Reel(s)
  - Sharpening a stick, 1951-05-19; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:59; Curry, Ed; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
    Allegany Indian Reservation (N.Y.); Seneca dance; Seneca Indians--Music
  - Choosing-a-partner and Women's Dance, 1951-05-19; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:45; Curry, Ed; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Jimerson, Avery
  - Ed Curry's songs of 1947, 1951-05-19; 01-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:45; Curry, Ed; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Jimerson, Avery
  - Old Time (Women's Dance) Songs, 1951-05-19; 01-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:36; Curry, Ed; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Jimerson, Avery
  - Seneca Songs, 1950-06-12; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:15:34; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Sundown, Roland
    Includes Medicine Song, Pigeon Song, and other songs. Also includes some speech in Seneca and an interview regarding the consultant's life history.
    Santa Fe (N.M.); Seneca dance; Seneca Indians--Education; Seneca Indians--Folklore; Seneca Indians--Music; Seneca Indians--Rites and ceremonies
  - Seneca War Dance Cycle and discussion, 1951-05-19; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:42; Curry, Ed; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
    Allegany Indian Reservation (N.Y.); Seneca dance; Seneca Indians--Music; Seneca Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Song cycles
  - Corn Dance, 1954-03-23; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:01; Bartlett, Charles; Cornplanter, Jesse J.; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
  - Standing Quiver Dance, 1954-03-23; 04-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:23; Bartlett, Charles; Cornplanter, Jesse J.; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
    Seneca dance; Seneca Indians--Music; Stomp dance; Tonawanda Indian Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Ganeho (Show) song with drum, 1954-03-23; 04-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:22; Bartlett, Charles; Cornplanter, Jesse J.; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
  - Hunting or Canoeing Song, 1954-03-23; 04-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:13; Bartlett, Charles; Cornplanter, Jesse J.; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
  - Song of Departure from Genesseo to Buffalo Creek, to Datgahso, 1954-03-23; 04-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:56; Bartlett, Charles; Cornplanter, Jesse J.; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
  - Pigeon Dance, 1954-03-23; 04-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:40; Bartlett, Charles; Cornplanter, Jesse J.; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
  - Farewell in Ganeho, 1954-03-23; 04-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:31; Bartlett, Charles; Cornplanter, Jesse J.; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
  - Seneca Oldtime Women's Dance (gainogayoka eskänye), 1954-03-23; 04-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:59; Bartlett, Charles; Cornplanter, Jesse J.; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
  - Raccoon Dance, 1954-03-23; 04-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:23; Bartlett, Charles; Cornplanter, Jesse J.; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
  - Special Recording of Iroquois Dawn Song for Sally Bartlett, 1954-03-23; 04-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:34; Bartlett, Charles; Cornplanter, Jesse J.; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
  - Standing Quiver Dance (antiphonal), 1954-03-23; 04-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:28; Bartlett, Charles; Cornplanter, Jesse J.; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
  - Yaweho, 1954-03-23; 04-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:05; Bartlett, Charles; Cornplanter, Jesse J.; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
  - Seneca War Dance, 1954-03-23; 04-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:50; Bartlett, Charles; Cornplanter, Jesse J.; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
  - Fish Dance, 1954-03-23; 04-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:05; Bartlett, Charles; Cornplanter, Jesse J.; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
  - Hand-in-Hand Dance, 1954-03-23; 04-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:13; Bartlett, Charles; Cornplanter, Jesse J.; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
  - Corn Dance, 1954-03-23; 04-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:10; Bartlett, Charles; Cornplanter, Jesse J.; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
  - Midwinter Festival: False Face; Beggars Dance; Indian Tobacco, 1954-03-23; 04-17; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:43; Bartlett, Charles; Cornplanter, Jesse J.; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
  - Fish Dance, 1954-03-23; 04-18; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:23; Bartlett, Charles; Cornplanter, Jesse J.; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
  - Seneca War Dance, 1954-03-23; 04-19; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:28; Bartlett, Charles; Cornplanter, Jesse J.; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
  - Trotting Dance, 1951-05-19; 05-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:53; Curry, Ed; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Jimerson, Avery
    Quaker Bridge (N.Y.); Seneca dance; Seneca Indians--Music; Seneca Indians--Social life and customs
  - Discussion of Trotting Dance, 1951-05-19; 05-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:23; Curry, Ed; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
  - Hand-in-Hand Dance, 1951-05-19; 05-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:12:59; Curry, Ed; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Jimerson, Avery
  - Discussion of Hand-in-Hand Dance, 1951-05-19; 05-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:55; Curry, Ed; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
- Klamath Indian Political Texts, August 11, 1950; Mss.Rec.138.8; 5.0 Reel(s)
  - Klamath Tribal Council History, 1950-08-11; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:44; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Lang, Tom
    Klamath Indian Reservation (Or.); Klamath Indians--Government relations; Klamath Indians--History; Klamath Indians--Land tenure; Klamath Indians--Politics and government; Modoc Indians--History
  - Treaty of 1864 with Klamath Indians, 1950-08-11; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:33; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Lang, Tom
    Includes a Klamath song from 23:26 to 23:55. Discussion of Klamath music begins at 23:13.
    Klamath Indian Reservation (Or.); Klamath Indians--Education; Klamath Indians--Government relations; Klamath Indians--History; Klamath Indians--Music; Klamath Indians--Social conditions
- Blackfoot Songs and Dances, August 1950; Mss.Rec.138.9; 3.0 Reel(s)
  - Conversation on Klamath singing, with one song, 1950-08-16; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:55; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Hecote, Ellen
    Klamath Indians--Music; Klamath Indians--Social life and customs; Sprague River (Or.: Town)
  - Conversation on healing and songs, 1950-08-16; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:28; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Hecote, Ellen
    Klamath Indian Reservation (Or.); Klamath Indians--Medicine; Klamath Indians--Music; Klamath Indians--Social life and customs
  - Reading of notes on the beginning of factions on the Klamath Reservation, 1950-08; 01-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:24; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
    Klamath Indian Reservation (Or.); Klamath Indians--Government relations; Klamath Indians--History; Modoc Indians--History; Modoc Indians--Wars, 1873
  - Reading of notes on Watson Duffy, 1950-08; 01-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:14:09; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
    Klamath Indian Reservation (Or.); Modoc Indians--Government relations; Modoc Indians--Politics and government; Modoc Indians--Social conditions; Paiute Indians--Politics and government
  - Reading of notes on David Chocktoot, 1950-08; 01-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:31; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
    Klamath Indian Reservation (Or.); Paiute Indians--History; Paiute Indians--Politics and government
  - Grass Dance, 1950-08-30; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:08; Bear Child, Lewis; Bull Child, George; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Running Crane, Geneva; Running Crane, John
    Browning (Mont.); Siksika Indians--Music
  - Rabbit Dance, 1950-08-30; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:27; Bear Child, Lewis; Bull Child, George; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Running Crane, Geneva; Running Crane, John
  - Grass Dance again, 1950-08-30; 02-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:27; Bear Child, Lewis; Bull Child, George; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Running Crane, Geneva; Running Crane, John
  - Donation Song, 1950-08-30; 02-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:24; Bear Child, Lewis; Bull Child, George; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Running Crane, Geneva; Running Crane, John
    Browning (Mont.); Siksaka Indians--Social life and customs; Siksika Indians--Music
  - Brave Dogs, 1950-08-30; 02-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:26; Bear Child, Lewis; Bull Child, George; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Running Crane, Geneva; Running Crane, John
  - Serenade Songs of Young Men, 1950-08-30; 02-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:29; Bear Child, Lewis; Bull Child, George; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Running Crane, Geneva; Running Crane, John
  - Victory Song on Horseback and Victory Dance, 1950-08-30; 02-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:26; Bear Child, Lewis; Bull Child, George; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Running Crane, Geneva; Running Crane, John
    Browning (Mont.); Siksaka Indians--History; Siksika Indians--Music
  - Pipe Dance, 1950-08-30; 02-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:53; Bear Child, Lewis; Bull Child, George; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Running Crane, Geneva; Running Crane, John
  - Dove Dance, 1950-08-30; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:00; Bear Child, Lewis; Bull Child, George; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Running Crane, Geneva; Running Crane, John
  - Blackfeet Sun Dance, 1950-08-30; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:06; Bear Child, Lewis; Bull Child, George; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Running Crane, Geneva; Running Crane, John
  - Adoption and name-giving for Douglas B. Fenton, 1950-08-30; 03-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:35; Bull Child, George; Fenton, Douglas B.; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Running Crane, John
    Adoption rites; Browning (Mont.); Siksika Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Siksika language
  - Five words in Crow, 1950-08-30; 03-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:05; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Schenadoah, Rodney
    Browning (Mont.); Crow language; Seneca language
  - Grass Dance, 1950-08-30; 03-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:37; Bear Child, Lewis; Bull Child, George; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Running Crane, Geneva; Running Crane, John
  - Owl Dance, 1950-08-30; 03-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:13; Bear Child, Lewis; Bull Child, George; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Running Crane, Geneva; Running Crane, John
- Indian Summer School Dance Program. Various Tribes. New Mexico., June 28, 1950; Mss.Rec.138.10; 5.0 Reel(s)
  - Reading of notes resulting from interview with Henry Hughes, 1950-06-28; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:38; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
    Indians of North America--New Mexico--Government relations; Lawyers--New Mexico; Pueblo Indians--Government relations; Santa Fe (N.M.); Taos Indians--Social life and customs
  - Jemez Buffalo Dance, 1950-06-28; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:11:08; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Smith, George
    Buffalo dance; Indians of North America--New Mexico--Music; Jemez dance; Jemez Indians--Music; Powwows--New Mexico; Santa Fe (N.M.)
  - Taos Community work, 1950-06-26; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:56; Concha, Eliseo; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
    Anthropological linguistics; Santa Fe (N.M.); Taos Indians--Politics and government; Taos Indians--Social life and customs; Tiwa language
  - Introductory remarks by M.C., 1950-06-28; 02-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:52; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Smith, George
    Powwows--New Mexico; Santa Fe (N.M.)
  - Navaho (Preliminary), 1950-06-28; 02-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:55; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
    Indians of North America--New Mexico--Music; Navajo Indians--Music; Powwows--New Mexico; Santa Fe (N.M.)
  - Five Civilized Tribes. Jokes., 1950-06-28; 02-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:03; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Smith, George
    Powwows--New Mexico; Santa Fe (N.M.); Wit and humor